# Juan Sebastián Calderón Rivera

Date of Birth: December 29<sup>th</sup>, 1991

**Phone**: +57 310 223 5856

**E-Mail**: ing.calderon.sebastian@gmail.com

## PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Industrial Engineer with marketing & sales knowledge and experience, product strategy development, market research and competitive environment analysis. Expertise in the design, analysis and develop of highly productive processes through optimal and efficient use of human, physical, technological and financial resources, focused on production management, optimization, quality and logistics. Strong leadership, self-motivated, good communication skills, open to changes, willing to learn, very persistent and always focused on results.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

**SIEMENS S.A.** Marketing Coordinator.

#### **Activities:**

- Lead the marketing area for the BU (Business Unit) of transformers.
- Define, design and execute the customer loyalty program of Siemens.
- Manage the Siemens Transformers website and RFQs.
- Lead and execute the strategic year plan for the BU, follow up of initiatives and activities defined on it.
- Analyze markets for the BU for the country and the Cluster to the market planning (Market Intelligence).
- Follow up and analyze key performance indicators for the transformers business.
- Analyze the price change for each product line in the countries of the Austral Andean region, central America, the Caribbean and north America.
- Effective management and control of marketing activities budget.
- Lead, coordinate and organize events, courses and publications concerning to the marketing communications.
- Strategic plan to increase customer loyalty.
- Use of CRM Tools to review and validate processes of business planning for the BU in the country, cluster and head quarter.
- Lead the sales quality group to treat non conformances, Net Promoter Score (NPS) and prepare the requirements for auditing and customer homologation processes.

Dates: August 2015 - Now.

#### SIEMENS S.A. University apprentice.

#### **Activities:**

- To Design and execute "LEAN MANAGEMENT DE DESPACHOS" Project regarding Transformers dispatch.
- Develop market research reports for Colombia and the Region. Analyze variables of market, clients and competitors. Projections of sales based on econometric methods.
- Use of CRM Tools (PHILOS) to review and validate processes of business planning for the BU in the country, cluster and head quarter.
- Strategic support in the sales indicators analysis.
- Sector analysis and organizational diagnostic for SIEMENS S.
- Improvement plan concerning to the implementation of qualitative models in the market research methodology.

Date: January 2015 - July 2015

## ISPERE (Joinville, Brazil)

Role: Intern in "Instituto Pedagógico de Reabilitação e inclusão"

#### **Activities:**

- Budget Management
- Bank Statements Management
- External Relationship Management
- Marketing Strategies

Dates: August 2013 – November 2013

**Phone:** +55 47 3422-1990

## EDUCATION AND TRAINING

#### UNIVERSITY

**Industrial Engineering -** Escuela Colombiana de Ingeniería Julio Garavito, Bogotá D.C., 2009 - 2015

#### HIGH SCHOOL

High School Graduate. Colegio Champagnat de Bogotá D.C., 1997 - 2008

## **LANGUAGES**

**SPANISH:** 

**Level**: Mother Language

ENGLISH: Level: B2\*

**PORTUGUESE:** 

Level: B1\*

\*Levels: A1/A2: Basic user - B1/B2: Independent user - C1/C2: Proficient user

## **SEMINARIES AND COURSES**

**Feria Internacional del Sector Eléctrico** - *Energía Solar: Fuente de Desarrollo y Sostenibilidad* — Medellín, Colombia

Siemens Transformers Academy. Lean Basics Introduction – Tenjo, Colombia

## **COMPUTERS SKILLS AND SOFTWARES**

Excellent handling of Microsoft Office™ programs Microsoft Office™(Excel, Word, Power Point, Publisher, Outlook, Visual Basic.) and:

- SIMIO Simulation Software
- Visual Studio
- AutoCAD
- Solid Works
- Minitab
- GAMS
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Illustrator
- CRM Tools (Oracle PHILOS, Siemens Offers & Orders), Windows SharePoint Services

# **PROFESSIONAL REFERENCES**

## JAIRO ALFONSO SANDOVAL RODRGUEZ

**Role:** Regional Sales Manager – Transformers

**Company:** Siemens S.A. **Phone:** +57 311 876 9376

# **PERSONAL REFERENCES**

## JULIO ANDRES RIAÑO SANCHEZ

**Role:** Inside Sales – Sales Support

Company: IBM

**Phone:** 312 532 5091

## **EUGENIO CALDERON RODRIGUEZ**

Role: Independent Phone: 310 206 1420